<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University on Sacha&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/hugo-texify3/tags/university/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University on Sacha&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/hugo-texify3/tags/university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why you Should do an Industrial Placement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hugo-texify3/posts/placement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hugo-texify3/posts/placement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-employment&#34;&gt;Future Employment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of experience in a relevant field sets you apart from lots of other graduates competing for those crucial entry level roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your placement employer liked you, they may offer you part time employment in your third year at university and/or a graduate role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working in industry also lets you begin to develop contacts with more senior engineers. There&amp;rsquo;s always a chance this will net you a job sometime in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-benefits&#34;&gt;Academic Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A year working with experts will likely improve your technical capacity and therefore final overall degree grades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve also had to manage your time in a much more rigourous fashion than other students which makes keeping assignment deadlines and attending the dreaded 9am lecture much easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tips-for-applying&#34;&gt;Tips for Applying&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be persistent - you will probably get a lot of rejections and it can be a little demoralizing, but if you keep at it you will most likely find something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just apply for big companies - they often have much more rigiorous application processes which get a lot more applicants you&amp;rsquo;ll  be competing against. Plus, at smaller companies you often get a wider variety of duties and more freedom within the role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t lie on your CV - if you get an interview it isn&amp;rsquo;t a good look if you can&amp;rsquo;t answer a question about something in which you&amp;rsquo;ve claimed to be an expert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be yourself - companies want to see the real you in an interview scenario, they&amp;rsquo;ll likely notice if you&amp;rsquo;re holding back. They&amp;rsquo;ll like someone who&amp;rsquo;s easy to talk to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much - interviewers expect you to be a bit nervous, especially if this is your first big job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use an app like Trello to keep track of your applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to have your CV reviewed by your department and any industry contacts you may already have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
